export const chapter = "Chapter - 3: Adaptations in Animals";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "What are the three main groups of adaptations in animals mentioned in the text?",
          optionA:
            "Adaptations to weather, Adaptations for movement, Adaptations for survival",
          optionB:
            "Adaptations to the living habitat, Adaptations for food, Adaptations for protection",
          optionC:
            "Adaptations to different climates, Adaptations for breathing, Adaptations for hunting",
          correctAnswer:
            "B) Adaptations to the living habitat, Adaptations for food, Adaptations for protection",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the primary purpose of adaptations in animals?",
          optionA: "To make them look attractive",
          optionB: "To help them communicate",
          optionC: "To adjust and survive in their surroundings",
          correctAnswer: "C) To adjust and survive in their surroundings",
        },
        {
          question: "Which group of animals is considered arboreal?",
          optionA: "Fish and whales",
          optionB: "Monkeys and sloths",
          optionC: "Lions and tigers",
          correctAnswer: "B) Monkeys and sloths",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What adaptation do desert animals like camels have to survive in extreme conditions?",
          optionA: "Aestivation",
          optionB: "Thick skin and coarse hair",
          optionC: "Hibernation",
          correctAnswer: "B) Thick skin and coarse hair",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the adaptation of birds for flying in the air?",
          optionA: "Hollow bones",
          optionB: "Fur on their bodies",
          optionC: "Webbed feet",
          correctAnswer: "A) Hollow bones",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What adaptation do amphibians have for breathing in water?",
          optionA: "Gills",
          optionB: "Lungs",
          optionC: "Blowhole",
          correctAnswer: "A) Gills",
        },
        {
          question: "Which region is considered a cold desert in the text?",
          optionA: "Rainforest",
          optionB: "Polar regions",
          optionC: "Deserts",
          correctAnswer: "B) Polar regions",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the term used for the seasonal movement of birds?",
          optionA: "Adaptation",
          optionB: "Migration",
          optionC: "Hibernation",
          correctAnswer: "B) Migration",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why do some animals have quills or spines on their bodies?",
          optionA: "To attract mates",
          optionB: "For camouflage",
          optionC: "For protection against predators",
          correctAnswer: "C) For protection against predators",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary adaptation of herbivores for obtaining food?",
          optionA: "Sharp tearing teeth",
          optionB: "Long sucking tubes",
          optionC: "Sharp biting teeth",
          correctAnswer: "C) Sharp biting teeth",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Animals living in deserts, such as camels, foxes, snakes, lizards, and moles, have ____________ skin and coarse hair to protect themselves from the extreme heat and cold.",
          optionA: "smooth",
          optionB: "thick",
          optionC: "slimy",
          correctAnswer: "B) thick",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Aquatic animals like fish and crabs have ____________ that help them breathe underwater.",
          optionA: "lungs",
          optionB: "gills",
          optionC: "blowholes",
          correctAnswer: "B) gills",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Amphibians such as frogs and toads breathe with the help of lungs while on land and with their moist skin when in water. Many amphibians have ____________ feet that help them swim in water.",
          optionA: "webbed",
          optionB: "clawed",
          optionC: "hoofed",
          correctAnswer: "A) webbed",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Aerial animals like birds have forelimbs modified into ____________ that help them fly.",
          optionA: "fins",
          optionB: "wings",
          optionC: "paws",
          correctAnswer: "B) wings",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Arboreal animals, such as monkeys and sloths, have strong limbs for holding branches and some may have curly tails which help them ____________ on the branches.",
          optionA: "swing",
          optionB: "crawl",
          optionC: "hop",
          correctAnswer: "A) swing",
        },
        {
          question:
            "__________ regions, like the polar regions, are considered cold deserts, and animals like polar bears and Arctic foxes have thick fur on their bodies for insulation from the cold.",
          optionA: "Desert",
          optionB: "Polar",
          optionC: "Rainforest",
          correctAnswer: "B) Polar",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Animals like seals and walruses store extra energy in the form of a thick layer of fat under their skin to stay warm during the extremely cold ____________.",
          optionA: "summers",
          optionB: "winters",
          optionC: "autumns",
          correctAnswer: "B) winters",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Fish and crabs have gills, while whales and dolphins have lungs. Whales and dolphins come up to the surface of the water to breathe through a hole called the ____________ on their heads.",
          optionA: "blowhole",
          optionB: "snorkel",
          optionC: "air vent",
          correctAnswer: "A) blowhole",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Animals that live on trees, such as monkeys and koalas, are called ____________ animals.",
          optionA: "aquatic",
          optionB: "terrestrial",
          optionC: "arboreal",
          correctAnswer: "C) arboreal",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Animals that eat only plants or depend on plants for their food are called ____________, and they have sharp biting teeth in the front and strong grinding teeth at the back for eating plants.",
          optionA: "carnivores",
          optionB: "herbivores",
          optionC: "omnivores",
          correctAnswer: "B) herbivores",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "The adaptation of animals to their habitat includes features such as body, behavior, and habits.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Deserts are usually hot during the day and cold at night, receiving ample rainfall.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Polar bears and Arctic foxes have thick fur on their bodies to adapt to the cold polar regions.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Amphibians like frogs and toads have webbed feet to help them move on land.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Aerial animals like birds have wings modified from forelimbs for flying.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Arboreal animals, such as monkeys and sloths, have strong limbs for holding branches.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Seals and walruses store extra energy in the form of a thick layer of fat for warmth during hot summers.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Fish and crabs have gills for breathing underwater, while whales and dolphins have lungs.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The north direction on a map is usually located at the bottom.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Maps are essential tools for understanding history and mathematics.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
